Defy the gods.
The Odyssey is a adventure, drama, fantasy film directed by Christopher Nolan.
Odysseus, the legendary Greek king of Ithaca, embarks on a long and perilous journey home following the Trojan War, chronicling his encounters with
mythical beings such as the Cyclops Polyphemus, the Sirens, and the witch-goddess Circe, while attempting to reunite with his wife, Penelope.
Odysseus, played by Matt Damon.
Telemachus, played by Tom Holland.
Athena, played by Zendaya.
Penelope, played by Anne Hathaway.
Antinous, played by Robert Pattinson.
The Odyssey is an upcoming epic fantasy action film
written and directed by Christopher Nolan.
An adaptation of Homer's ancient Greek epic the Odyssey, the film stars Matt Damon as Odysseus, the Greek king of Ithaca, and chronicles his
long and perilous journey home after the Trojan War as he attempts to reunite with his wife, Penelope, portrayed by Anne Hathaway.
The ensemble cast also features Tom Holland, Robert Pattinson, Lupita
Nyong'o, Zendaya, and Charlize Theron, among others.
Nolan and his wife Emma Thomas produce the film
through their production company, Syncopy.
Nolan began writing The Odyssey in March 2024, secured the project with
Universal Pictures by October, and the film was announced in December.
Casting occurred throughout late 2024, and Damon was
confirmed for the lead role in February 2025.
Filming took place from February to August 2025 across multiple international locations,
including Morocco, Greece, Italy, Scotland, Iceland, and Western Sahara.
With an estimated budget of $250 million, the film is the most expensive of Nolan's
career and his first to be shot entirely on IMAX's 70 mm film cameras.
The Odyssey is scheduled to be theatrically released in the
United States by Universal Pictures on July 17, 2026.
The film explores themes of greek, based on song, poem
or rhyme, peplum, ancient, epic poem.
The tone is emotional.